Costa Software Developer



contact

Largo Ferreira Lapa, 70 3Esq 4150 - 323 Porto Portugal

> **(**+351) 924 241 327 S rui.d.a.costa

ruidacosta

languages

in ruidcosta

Portuguese mother tongue English & Spanish fluency French basic

programming

JavaScript, C++. PHP. Java. C#, PL/SQL, Python, CSS & HTML5

frameworks

NodeJS, AngularJS, JQuery, Diango

tools

Sqlite, MySql, Oracle, MongoDB, Git. SVN.

presentation

A versatile and professional graduate software developer with 3 years of commercial experience. Worked with C++, C#, Javascript and PL/SQL on Windows environments. Unix and Unix-like user with 6+ years of personal experience.

A proven ability to maintain and enhance company software with the aim of improving operational functionality in line with business requirement.

Able to work with any technology and to perform full software development life cycle activates.

Currently looking for a software developer opportunity that will allow me to work alongside an expert team of developers. Thereby helping to drive my career progression to more seniors roles in the future.

experience

Full Time

☑ ruiduartecosta@gmail.com 2013–Now Finantech - Software Developer

Porto, Portugal Build functions and procedures on Oracle Databases for all company's trading systems. Add features, using C#, on a software designed to enable clients to configure their business rules. Fix bugs on trading server-side software, using C# and C++. Maintain existing libraries for communication interfaces with market data providers updated, using C++. Develop a Web Interface for all server side trading systems, using AngularJS and JQuery on front-end and C++ on backend. Server side application to insert real-time market data on a DB2 database system. Support clients in European and American financial markets. **Key Skills:** C++, C#, Oracle Databases, HTML, Javascript, JQuery, AngularJS, DB2 Databases, Fix Protocol, HTTP, REST API, Multi-Threading

Part Time

2006-2010 Freelancer - Backend developers

Develop back-end for some small websites in PHP. Key Skills: PHP, MySQL, Apache, HTML, Javascript

education

2010-2013 Master of Software Engineer Specialized in Network and Distributed Systems.

Docker 2006–2010 Bachelor of Software Engineer

University of Porto, Portugal

University of Porto, Portugal

interests

professional: software development, software design, web app creation, high-throughput computing, high-performance computing, parallel computing personal: playing music, cooking, trekking, spearfishing